Guide to the Richard Kluger Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional Material, Accession 1997-M-023
  - Company files [contents vary from folder to folder, but may include correspondence, printed materials, working papers, biographical information, and Kluger interview materials]
    - Smoking behavior
      - "Physicians Attitudes and Practices With Regard to Cigarette Smoking", 1963 (Box 30, Folder 403)
      - Smoking Behavior and Policy ["Discussion Paper Series"], 1986-1987 (Box 30, Folder 404)
      - "Trends in Public Attitudes on the Possibility of a Health Hazard in Cigarette Smoking", 1962, 1964 (Box 30, Folder 405-406)
      - "Why Do Juveniles Start Smoking", 1986 (Box 30, Folder 407)
    - Legislative/regulation
      - Congress
        - Chronology of action [Kluger notes], 1959-1986 (Box 30, Folder 408)
        - Legal and Monetary Affairs Subcommittee, 1957 (Box 30, Folder 409)
        - Public Health Cigarette Smoking Act of 1969 [Kluger notes] (Box 30, Folder 410)
      - Consumer Product Safety Commission, 1974-1975, undated (Box 31, Folder 411)
      - Federal Trade Commission
        - Advertising, 1927-1988 (Box 31, Folder 412-417)
        - Calfee, John E. [working paper on cigarette advertising], 1985 (Box 31, Folder 418)
        - Cigarette testing program, 1955, 1981-1985 (Box 31, Folder 419-421)
        - Cigarette testing program laboratory, 1987 (Box 31, Folder 422)
        - Philip Morris [testimonies by individuals]
          - Carlson, Anton J., 1943 (Box 31, Folder 423)
          - Lenth, C. William, 1946 (Box 31, Folder 424)
          - Tobey, George Loring, Jr., 1943 (Box 31, Folder 425)
        - R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Company [testimonies by individuals]
          - Barber, Walter Lanier, 1944 (Box 31, Folder 426)
          - Stansbury, Helen and Bourke-White, Margaret, 1944 (Box 31, Folder 427)
      - United States Department of Health and Human Services ["Major Local Smoking Ordinances in the United States"], 1989 (Box 31, Folder 428)
      - United States government actions on smoking issues [Kluger notes] (Box 31, Folder 429)
      - Cipollone vs. Liggett Group, Philip Morris, and Loews
        - Legal Notes [includes definitions of terminology, historical perspective of tobacco products liability cases and issues in tobacco litigation, summary notes of related material] (Box 32, Folder 430-431)
        - Pretrial
          - Correspondence, 1985, 1987 (Box 32, Folder 432)
          - General [summary notes by Kluger] (Box 32, Folder 433)
          - Documents/articles (Box 32, Folder 434-438)
        - Trial proceedings
          - Notes [by Kluger] (Box 33, Folder 439)
          - Transcripts [poor quality photocopies, pages missing]
            - 1988 Feb 1-2, 4-5 (Box 33, Folder 440-443)
            - 1988 Feb 9-18 (Box 33, Folder 444-446)
            - 1988 Feb 11? (Box 33, Folder 447)
              Mold, Dr. James [testimony]
            - 1988 Feb 23 (Box 33, Folder 448)
              Cullman, Joseph F., III [summary of testimony]
            - 1988 Feb 24-25, 29 (Box 33, Folder 449-450)
            - 1988 Mar 1 (Box 33, Folder 451)
            - 1988 Mar 2-8 (Box 34, Folder 452-453)
            - 1988 Mar 21-23 (Box 34, Folder 454-458)
            - 1988 Apr 4-6 (Box 34, Folder 459-460)
            - 1988 Apr 18, 20-21 (Box 35, Folder 461-462)
            - 1988 May 2, 4, 6, 18-? (Box 35, Folder 463-465)
            - 1988 May? (Box 35, Folder 466)
            - 1988 Jun 3, 6, ? (Box 35, Folder 467-468)
          - On writ of Certiorari to the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit Joint Appendix, 1990 (Box 35, Folder 469)
        - Trial and related events
          - General [summary notes by Kluger] (Box 36, Folder 470)
          - Documents and printed material, 1987-1992 (Box 36, Folder 471-474)
        - Daynard, Richard [Director of the Tobacco Products Liability Project (TPLP)]
          - General [summary notes by Kluger of documents released by TPLP] (Box 36, Folder 475)
          - Printed [material released by TPLP]
            - 1934-1964 (Box 36, Folder 476-480)
            - 1965-1981 (Box 37, Folder 481-485)
          - Statement on the implications of the Cipollone documents for future tobacco cases, 1988 March 26 (Box 37, Folder 486)
          - Philip Morris rebuttal to Daynard, 1988? (Box 37, Folder 487)
        - Depositions
          - U.S. District Court for District of New Jersey, Civil Action No. 83-2864
            - Cullman, Joseph F., III, 1984 October 24-26 (Box 37, Folder 488-490)
            - Dunn, William L., Jr., 1987 November 20 (Box 38, Folder 491)
            - Osdene, Thomas S., 1984 October 3-4 (Box 38, Folder 492-493)
            - Schuman, Leonard M., 1987 June 16-18 (Box 38, Folder 494-496)
            - Schuman, Leonard M., 1988 January 13 (Box 39, Folder 497)
          - Superior Court of New Jersey, Essex County, Docket No. L-006851-83 [Heimann, Robert K. deposition in Flynn, George S. vs. American Brands, Inc. et. al.], 1985 April 17-18 (Box 39, Folder 498-499)
    - Bibliographic
      - General [Kluger's notes on books read; listed by topic, includes index] (Box 39, Folder 500)
      - History of Tobacco and Tobacco Industry (Box 39, Folder 501-502)
      - Pre-World War I (Box 39, Folder 503)
      - Smoking and Health (Box 39, Folder 504-506)
      - Government and Tobacco (Box 39, Folder 507)
      - Cigarette Advertising (Box 40, Folder 508)
      - Smoking Behavior and Social Context (Box 40, Folder 509)
      - Quitting (Box 40, Folder 510)
      - Scientific articles [Kluger's card file arranged in two alphabetical runs; one run is numbered, one is not]
        - Numbered (Box 40, Folder 511-513)
        - Unnumbered (Box 40, Folder 514-516)
      - Additional materials
        - American Tobacco Company - Sold American! - The First Fifty Years, 1904-1954, 1954 (Box 40, Folder 517)
        - Canadian Council on Smoking and Health "Proceedings on the 5th World Conference", 1983
          - Vol. I (Box 41, Folder 518)
          - Vol. II (Box 41, Folder 519)
        - Smoke Signals: Cigarettes, Advertising and the American Way of Life [exhibit catalog], 1990 (Box 41, Folder 520)
        - U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare - The National Conference on Smoking and Health [Proceedings], 1966 May 1-3 (Box 41, Folder 521)
    - Fire Retardancy Cigarette Research [pertaining to flame retardancy of fabric, ignition propensity, and related topics; pages missing], Circa 1970s-1980s
      - General (Box 41, Folder 522-523)
      - General (Box 42, Folder 524-526)
      - Loose, uncorrelated pages (Box 42, Folder 527)
      - Deposition [Superior Court of New Jersey, Hudson County, Docket No. L-039135-85]
        - Greene, Randall K., 1988 July 21-22 (Box 42, Folder 528-529)
    - Audio-Visual materials
      - American Cancer Society [anti-smoking TV spots; video], 1966-1983 (Box 43.1)
        - Use copy (Box 43.1U)
      - Anti-smoking radio commercials, 1968-1970 [by advertiser Tony Schwartz; audio], 1988 (Box 43.2)
      - California Department of Health Services [Tobacco Education Media Campaign commercials; video], undated (Box 43.3)
      - "Death in the West" [British documentary on Marlboro cigarette commercials; video], undated (Box 43.4)
      - Newhart, Bob [spoof interview with Sir Walter Raleigh], undated; 1 (Box 44)
      - Tobacco Institute [Connie Drath and Will Dwyer rebut antismoking charges], 1984; 1 (Box 46)
      - United States Office on Smoking and Health [Department of Health and Human Services], 1987; 1 (Box 47)
      - Company files
        - Liggett and Myers
          - Kensler, Charles, J. [no. 543], 1989 June 12; 3 (Box 48–50)
    - Personal interviews
      - Henderson, Keith (Box 45, Folder 534)
        Permission of Richard Kluger is required to use interview of Keith Henderson.
      - Meyer, Larry (Box 45, Folder 535)
        Permission of Richard Kluger is required to use interview of Larry Meyer.